After addressing missing data first,
先处理好缺失的数据
cleaning for tidiness is usually the next logical step.
通常来说 接下来的清理步骤就是提高整洁度
Since Hadley Wickham is the pioneer of tidy data,
鉴于 Hadley Wickham 是整洁数据的先驱者
let's start this bit with a quote from his paper on the subject.
我们先来看看他的话 这里引用了他研究这一主题的论文
A huge amount of effort is spent cleaning data to get it ready for analysis,
作为分析的准备工作 数据清理耗费了我们大量的精力
but there has been little research on how to make data
但很少有人研究如何让数据清理
cleaning as easy and effective as possible.
尽可能地简单高效
This paper tackles a small,
这份论文解决的是数据清理的一小步
but important, component of data cleaning: data tidying.
但也是很重要的一步 提高数据整洁度
The key take away is that Tidy datasets are easy to manipulate.
这段话最关键的就是 整洁的数据集易于操作
And in the context of data wrangling,
把这点和数据整理联系起来
tidy datasets with data quality issues are almost always
虽有质量问题却整洁的小数据集
easier to clean than non-tidy as they have data quality issues.
往往要比有质量问题还不整洁的数据集容易清理
That means, it's generally best to clean the tidiness issues first,
也就是说 一般而言 最好先解决整洁度问题
which are our structural issues,
也就是结构问题
then clean the quality issues,
然后再去解决质量问题
which are the content issues.
也就是内容问题
For our example in this oral insulin clinical trial dataset,
看看我们这个口服胰岛素临床试验数据集的例子
we detected and documented four sections of the dataset that weren't tidy.
我们找出并记录了数据集四个不整洁的地方
The first in the patients table,
第一个是患者表
the two variables in one column,
一列里有两个变量
the contact column here,
也就是这个联系方式列中
phone number and email are in this one column.
放了电话号码和电子邮件两个变量
Then in the treatment's table,
然后是治疗表
there are three variables in two columns.
三个变量放在了两列里
Treatment and start dose and end dose in the auralin and novodra columns.
也即 auralin 和 novodra 列中的疗法、起始剂量和结束剂量
Start dose here, end dose here and
起始剂量在这 结束剂量在这
the third treatment variable in the column headers auralin novodra.
第三个变量 疗法则分别为列名 auralin 和 novodra
The third is that the adverse_reactions table shouldn't exist.
第三是不良反应表不该存在
And that the adverse reaction column should be part of the treatments table i.e.
治疗表中应有一列记录不良反应
this adverse_reaction column here should be joined with this treatments table here.
也就是说 这列不良反应应合并到这个治疗表里
And the fourth, is that the given_name and surname columns are duplicated in
第四是名 (given_name) 和姓氏 (surname)两列冗余
the treatments in adverse_reactions table when it should only be in the patients table.
治疗表和不良反应表里都有这两列 但它们只需在患者表中出现一次即可
And here the given_name and surname is displayed in the patients.info results.
这里是 patients.info 的结果 名和姓氏都出来了
Same goes for treatments.info and adverse_reactions.info.
treatments.info 和 adverse_reactions.info 里也出现了名和姓氏
So only a small set of tools are needed to deal with a wide range of untidy datasets.
要处理大量的不整洁数据集 只需一小套工具即可
You'll cover the most common ones in Pandas to fix these above four issues next.
接下来 你将使用 pandas 里最常见的几种工具来解决上述的四个问题